amsoil.com 2018-12-31

# AMSOIL Online Privacy Policy

### Effective May 25, 2018

AMSOIL INC. ("AMSOIL") and its associated brands are committed to protecting the privacy and security of the information provided by our customers. Your privacy is important to us, and we make every effort to safeguard the information you provide when interacting with our websites, contests and communications with our employees. Our Privacy Policy was developed to help you understand the types of information we might collect when you visit our websites, including AMSOIL.com, or interact with us in other ways. It also explains how we may use that information, whether we disclose it to anyone and the choices you have regarding our use of, and your ability to review, correct, object to, or erase that information. If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, please contact [info@marketing.amsoil.com](mailto:info@marketing.amsoil.com). 

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. If you subscribe to services, such as MyAMSOILGarage™, or have memberships, such as an AMSOIL Preferred Customer membership, we may notify you of Privacy Policy updates by email so you will be aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, it is disclosed. By your continued use of our websites and services and input of personal information, you are subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy, as amended from time to time. 

  1. Whose information is gathered by AMSOIL and for what purpose?
  2. What personal information does AMSOIL gather?
  3. How can my visit be associated with personal information?
  4. How does AMSOIL use information it collects?
  5. Sharing Information with Third Parties
  6. Social Media Features
  7. External websites
  8. Retention of personal information
  9. International Transfer of Information
  10. How Secure Is My Information with AMSOIL?
  11. What Choices Do I Have?
  12. Managing Your Personal Information with AMSOIL
  13. AMSOIL Anti-SPAM Policy
  14. Minors and AMSOIL Services
  15. Additional Information

#### Whose Information is Gathered by AMSOIL and for What Purpose?

AMSOIL collects information from individuals who engage with us on the Internet via our websites and the websites of our associated brands. We also collect data from individuals who request more information, such as requesting that a catalog be mailed to them, and those who subscribe to our publications, download additional information from our website, interact with us on social media and enter our contests. Additional information is also requested from anyone who subscribes to services we provide. This information is gathered for the purposes of enhancing the customer experience at AMSOIL.com and our affiliated websites, and to continually improve the quality of our products and services for our customers. AMSOIL does not sell information to outside parties at any time, for any reason. Additionally, users can adjust and remove information at their own discretion at any time by selecting the "Unsubscribe" or "Update my preferences" link included in our emails. 

##### back to top __

####  What Personal Information Does AMSOIL Gather?

We store any information you enter on our website through the actions you take and any submissions you make to forms, menus or other inputs. Examples include the following: 

  * **Information You Give Us**   
You provide most such information when you search, buy, post, participate in a contest or questionnaire or communicate with customer service. For example, you provide information when you search for a product; place an order through our online store; provide information in your account or profile; communicate with us by phone, email or otherwise; complete a questionnaire or a contest entry form; use our services such as MyAMSOILGarage™; and request information. As a result of those actions, you might supply us with such information as your name, address, phone number and email address; names of persons or businesses to whom purchases have been shipped, including addresses and phone numbers; email addresses of your associates and other people with whom you share our content; emails directly to us; credit card information or financial information, including Social Security or tax identification numbers, which might be needed if applying for credit or associated with different account types. 
  * **Navigational Information**   
Examples of navigational information we collect and analyze include the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; login; email address associated with your activities; password(s) to our services; computer and connection information, such as browser type, version and time zone setting; browser plug-in types and versions; operating system and platform; purchase history; the full Uniform Resource Locator (URL) clickstream to, through and from our website, including date and time; cookie number (when applicable); and pages/products you viewed or searched for during your visit. We may also use browser data such as cookies, Flash cookies (also known as Flash Local Shared Objects) or similar data on certain parts of our website for fraud prevention and other purposes. During some visits we may use software tools such as JavaScript to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks and mouseovers) and methods used to browse away from the page. We may also collect technical information to help us identify your device for fraud prevention and diagnostic purposes. 
  * **Mobile Information**  
Most mobile devices provide users with the ability to disable location services. These controls are often located in the device's settings menu. For information about specific devices, see your device manufacturer's support documentation or your carrier's website. If you have questions about how to disable your device's location services, we recommend you contact your mobile service carrier or your device manufacturer. If you have not disabled your device's location services, that information would be available to us 
  * **Call Center Logs**  
AMSOIL uses voice recording and tracking software for customer service training and improvement. In addition to information we collect on our website, our call recording software monitors all calls to the AMSOIL call center. When you call us to place an order or request technical service assistance, any information provided may be used in future interactions, such as assistance with order completion, answering inquiries or resolving a customer issue. This information may also be used to send you email about our products and services. You can opt out of receiving specific types of email by selecting the "Unsubscribe" link included in each email. We may link information we store with analytics software to personal information you submit at our call center. 
  * **Information from Other Sources**  
Examples of information we receive from other sources include updated delivery and address information from our carriers or other third parties, which we use to correct our records and deliver your next purchase or communication more easily; account information, purchase or redemption information and page-view information from some third parties with which we operate co-branded businesses or for which we provide technical, fulfillment, advertising or other services; search-term and search-result information from some searches conducted through the Web search features offered by Google™ Analytics; search results and links, including paid listings (such as Sponsored Links); and credit history information from credit bureaus, which we use to help prevent and detect fraud and to offer certain credit or financial services to some customers. 
  * **Offerings from Authorized Vendors**  
Examples of businesses with which we offer services or products include data supplied for Oil Analyzers Inc., the AMSOIL Dealer Print Center® and the Lowen™ Custom Vehicle Wraps portal for AMSOIL Dealers. Information shared with, and obtained from, these vendors is used only for the purpose of assisting in transactions and analyzing product offerings. 
  * **Account Information**  
Examples of account information you can access easily at AMSOIL.com include up-to-date information regarding recent orders; personally identifiable information (including name, email, password, account communications and personalized setting preferences for services and address book entries); payment settings (credit card numbers and CSV numbers are not stored with your account and need to be entered at each transaction, unless otherwise noted); email notification settings (which can be controlled from individual email updates and newsletters by opting out at any time or by contacting [info@marketing.amsoil.com](mailto:info@marketing.amsoil.com) and requesting that their information be changed or removed from our records); and any order details which have been saved in EZ Online Order Forms or wish lists. 

##### back to top __

####  How Can My Visit be Associated with Personal Information?

Because AMSOIL associates traffic from our visitors with a leads program for individual AMSOIL Dealers, various methods are employed to ensure that Dealers who are generating traffic to the main corporate website are associated with visitor activity. Internet browser cookies or query string parameters passed through a page URL are typically used to facilitate this association. Their individual uses are as follows: 

  * **Internet Browser Cookies**   
Cookies are unique identifiers that we occasionally transfer to your device to enable our systems to recognize your device and to provide various personalization features, including advertisements on other websites and storage of items in your Shopping Cart between visits. 

The Help feature on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie or how to disable cookies altogether. Additionally, you can disable or delete similar data used by browser add-ons, such as Flash cookies, by changing the add-ons' settings or visiting the website of their manufacturer. Because cookies allow you to take advantage of some of the advanced features of the AMSOIL website, we recommend that you leave them turned on. 

  * **Query String Parameters Passed in the Page URL**   
The following is an example of a typical URL for the AMSOIL website containing a query string: /shop/by-product/motor-oil/diesel/?filters=81. The bold portion of this URL page address at AMSOIL is passing user preference information to the website and changing the page layout accordingly. 

Parameters such as these are used to customize the user experience at the AMSOIL website by tailoring the content and interaction options available. These parameters are also used to attribute new visitors to AMSOIL.com via the websites of independent AMSOIL Dealers to the appropriate Dealer. Such visitors may be considered "leads" in the system after taking actions such as creating a new online account or requesting more information, and the information they supply will be shared with the Dealers who generated the website traffic. Leads will typically be contacted by a Dealer within one to three business days following a qualifying action. 

  * **Log Files**   
We may collect demographic information, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites, using log files that are not associated with your name or other personally identifying information. We also automatically collect information about your computer hardware and software. This information can include your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used by AMSOIL to maintain the quality of our marketing and product development, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the AMSOIL website. For these purposes, we link this automatically collected data to personal information, such as name, email address, address and phone number. 

  * **Third-Party Tracking Technologies**   
The use of cookies and web beacons by any tracking utility company is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these third-party tracking technologies. 

  * **Advertising**   
We partner with a third-party ad network to either display advertising on our website or manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect various specific information about your activities on this and other websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you do not want this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt out by clicking here: http://preferences.truste.com/, or by contacting [info@marketing.amsoil.com](mailto:info@marketing.amsoil.com) and requesting that your information be changed or removed from our records. Please note this does not opt you out of being served all advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads delivered by other websites' cookies. 

##### back to top __

####  How Does AMSOIL Use the Information It Collects?

AMSOIL uses the data we collect to run our business and improve our products, to send communications, and for advertising purposes. The information we collect will only be used in compliance with this Privacy Policy. Furthermore, AMSOIL will never sell your personal information to any third party. 

  * **Use of Personal Information**   
In addition to the uses identified elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, we may use your personal information to (a) improve your browsing experience by personalizing our websites and improve services; (b) send information to you which we think may be of interest to you by post, email or other means; (c) send you marketing communications relating to our business or the businesses of carefully selected third parties which we think may be of interest to you and (d) provide other companies with statistical information about our users. We may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offer that may be of interest to you. In those cases, we do not transfer your unique personal information to the third party. In addition, we may share data with trusted partners to contact you based on your request to receive such communications, help us perform statistical analysis or provide customer support. Such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except for these purposes, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information. 

  * **Use of Automatic Information**   
We use navigational information to operate and improve the websites and MyAMSOILGarage. We may also use navigational information alone or in combination with personal information to provide you with personalized information about AMSOIL and its products. 

  * **Customer Testimonials and Comments**   
We post customer testimonials and comments on our websites that may contain personal information. We obtain each customer's consent via email prior to posting the customer's name and testimonial. 

  * **Use of Credit Card Information**   
We use credit card information solely to collect payment from you. We use a third-party service provider to manage credit card processing. This service provider is not permitted to store, retain or use information you provide except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on our behalf. In addition to standard credit card processing, some services we provide to customers allow for automatic reordering of products or renewal of services and memberships. Where such services are provided, customers are presented with the terms and conditions as a prerequisite to enrollment, and have the capability to control which card information is kept on file and to unsubscribe at any time. Any third-party services we allow or accept for payment at our website will also have additional terms and conditions of processing available as part of their respective service agreements. 

##### back to top __

####  Sharing Information with Third Parties?

We may use third parties, such as independent companies or independent AMSOIL Dealers, to provide services to our customers and visitors to our websites. To this end, we may need to share your information, with your consent or as necessary to fulfill an order or furnish a service you have requested or authorized. Examples may include: 

  * Third-Party Service Providers 

We occasionally use other companies to perform functions and offer services on behalf of AMSOIL and our subsidiary businesses. Examples include oil analysis; Dealer promotional and advertising services such as the Dealer Print Center® and Lowen TM Custom Vehicle Wraps portal; various vendors for order fulfillment purposes and businesses that are involved in computer services for AMSOIL INC. and our subsidiary businesses. Vendors such as these have access to personal information only as needed to perform their functions and are prohibited from using it for other purposes. Additional terms and conditions may apply and are made available as part of each respective third-party service agreement. 

  * Sweepstakes and Contests Managed by Third-Party Providers 

AMSOIL may occasionally use a third-party provider to manage a promotional contest, sweepstakes or giveaway campaign. The third parties involved in these situations will have access to your personal information only as long as the contest is active and only AMSOIL will use the information for prize notification and marketing purposes. Individual contest rules will always be available at the time of entry for more details and opt-out opportunities. 

  * Social, Search and Display Networks 

Ordering online with AMSOIL or engaging in other activities with our digital properties can result in small amounts of personally identifiable information (email, phone number or name) being encrypted and shared anonymously with social and search networks such as Facebook™, Google and Twitter™. You may opt out of any information sharing of this nature by contacting [info@marketing.amsoil.com](mailto:info@marketing.amsoil.com) and requesting that your information be changed or removed from our records.   
In all cases where we share your information with other parties, we explicitly require that party to acknowledge and adhere to our privacy and customer data handling policies. AMSOIL may access, transfer, disclose and/or preserve personal data when doing so is required in order to (1) comply with applicable law or respond to legal inquiries from governmental bodies; (2) protect AMSOIL's customers from harassment or fraud; (3) block or halt attempts at the intrusion of our computer systems or networks; or, (4) protect the property or safety of AMSOIL, its users, or others. 

##### back to top __

####  Social Media Features

Our websites include social media features, such as the Facebook Like® button, and widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our sites. These features may collect your IP address and which page you are visiting on our sites. They also may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our websites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to these features. Your interactions with these features are governed by the Privacy Policy and other policies of the companies providing them. 

##### back to top __

####  External Websites

Our websites provide links to other websites. We do not control, and are not responsible for, the content or practices of these other websites. Our provision of such links does not constitute our endorsement of these other websites, their content, their owners or their practices. This Privacy Policy does not apply to these other websites, which are subject to the policies of their respective owners. 

##### back to top __

####  Retention of Personal Information

We retain personal information that you provide us as long as we consider it potentially useful in contacting you about AMSOIL products and services, after which time we securely delete the information. You may opt out of individual subscriptions from us by using the Unsubscribe link in every email we send, and additional information control options are available by contacting our customer service department. 

##### back to top __

####  International Transfer of Information

To facilitate our global operations, we may transfer and access personal information provided from customers outside the United States. Requests received from international customers will be processed by the AMSOIL International division and may be fulfilled by the AMSOIL International distributor network. Any transfer of personal information as it pertains to their services will fall under third-party privacy policies, which are created and maintained in accordance with the local laws or regulations of their respective territories. 

##### back to top __

####  How Secure Is My Information with AMSOIL?

A variety of sophisticated security measures are in place at AMSOIL to protect our website visitors, anyone who does business with AMSOIL or any of our affiliated businesses and partners. 

  * We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input. 
  * Credit card numbers and card security codes are required to be re-entered when confirming and processing payment for each online order. AMSOIL retains this information only long enough to transmit the credit card number to the appropriate credit card company during order processing. 
  * We require several examples of personal information as a safeguard to assist with password resetting, account maintenance and the opening of new accounts. 

##### back to top __

####  What Choices Do I Have?

  * As discussed above, you can always choose not to provide information, even though it might be needed to make a purchase or to take advantage of certain AMSOIL.com features. 
  * You can add or update certain information on pages such as those referenced in the "Which Information Can I Access?" section. 
  * If you do not want to receive email or other mail from us, please adjust your Customer Communication Preferences. (If you do not want to receive Conditions of Use and other legal notices from us, such as this Privacy Policy, those notices will still govern your use of AMSOIL.com, and it is your responsibility to review them for changes.) You may also unsubscribe directly from any emailed newsletters we manage as separate publication lists. 
  * If you do not want us to use personal information we gather to allow third parties to personalize advertisements we display to you, please adjust your Advertising Preferences. This can usually be done via settings in your browser. 
  * The Help feature on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie or how to disable cookies altogether. Additionally, you can disable or delete similar data used by browser add-ons, such as Flash cookies, by changing the add-ons' settings or visiting the website of their manufacturer. Because cookies allow you to take advantage of some of essential features, we recommend that you leave them turned on. 

##### back to top __

####  Managing Your Personal Information with AMSOIL

If you provide us with your personal information, you have the following rights with respect to that information: 

  * To access and review the personal information that you have supplied to us; 
  * To request that we correct any errors, outdated information or omissions in personal information that you have supplied to us; 
  * To request that your personal information not be used to contact you; 
  * To object to our processing of your personal information; and 
  * To request that we delete your data, provided that (a) we no longer require your data; (b) there is no legitimate legal basis for us to process your data; (c) we have unlawfully processed your data; or, (d) the data must be erased in order to comply with the law. In the event you have grounds to request that we delete your data, and would like us to do so, please contact the Data Protection Officer at the address provided below. Please be aware that full erasure may not be possible if your data is needed to comply with statutory requirements 

**Accessing and Correcting Personal Information:** Please contact the AMSOIL Data Protection Officer to make any requests related to your personal data. The Data Protection Officer can be reached at AMSOIL INC., ATTN: Data Privacy, 925 Tower Avenue, Superior, Wisconsin 54880 USA, or via email at [info@marketing.amsoil.com](mailto:info@marketing.amsoil.com). 

If you have a registered account on AMSOIL.com, you are free to amend any information contained in your account profile at any time by logging into your account and amending your account settings. 

##### back to top __

####  AMSOIL Anti-SPAM Policy

Our Privacy Policy requires that every email sent form AMSOIL have an "opt-out" mechanism and other required information. To opt out of individual newsletters please use the Unsubscribe link included in the email. However, you may still receive important customer information as it relates to your order or account. We are required to send out some email such as tax information by law; customers in our Dealer network cannot opt out of receiving these and other important communications. 

##### back to top __

####  Minors and AMSOIL Services

AMSOIL's products and services are not intended for children. Individuals under the age of thirteen (13) are prohibited from using AMSOIL.com. Users must be old enough to consent to the processing of their personal data in their country of residence, or secure the consent of their parent or guardian, where permitted. 

##### back to top __

####  Additional Information

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy or AMSOIL’s usage of your data, please contact us in writing at the address below. 

Regardless of your country of residence, the Data Controller responsible for your personal data is AMSOIL INC., which can be contacted at: 

##### back to top __
